#### **YASOO BHNAN**

Mobile: +9647512128791 Email: yesoo.bhnan@yahoo.com

Address: Erbil, Iraq GitHub: https://github.com/yasoua?tab=repositories

#### Snapshot

**Software Engineer**, designing, implementing and testing web applications as freelancer. with experience in increasing the ranking of sites in Google search, and also generate reports for customers related to all activities of the site about visitors. I have more than six successful systems implemented in Laravel framework.

IT and Network Administrator for Mikrotik, cisco, and Ubnt devices configuration. Also, I have CCNA certification.

#### **Technical Skills**

java, c++, js, html, css, bootstarp, jquery, ajax, python, php, django, Laravel, Pandas, Numpay, mathplothlib, siketlearn, vue.js, node.js, microsoft office, pack tracer, MYSQL, Oracle/ sql database, Linux and Windows operating systems, VMware, VirtualBox, WireShark, Penetrating Testing, Network protocols configuration, Photoshop.

# Experience

## Full-Stack Developer - Usofts, Erbil / Jan 2023 - Jan 2024

Html, CSS, bootstrap, JS, Vue.js, Node.js, Jquery, Ajax, php, Laravel, React, Google console, Google analytics I worked as a Full-Stack Developer in Usofts, designing and implementing websites and systems with admin panel

- I am using for the front-end React framework and best standards in designing website such as performance, accessibility, best practice and SEO.
- I am using for the back-end Laravel framework, MVC, function with less time complexity and implementing security, Auth, Moderator, ORM and CRUDS operation in addition to optimized and cleaned joining guery table.
- I am using Google search console for increasing the website Google search through adding robot files and using the best keyword and descriptions for the site.
- Using Google analytics and Google tag manager to navigate all the internal activities of the visitors on the site
- Generating client reports outlining and summarizing all website activities and traffic.

# Social Media Specialist – SPF, Erbil / Aug 2022 - Jan 2023

As a social media specialist, I was responsible for these tasks:

- · creating and designing social media posts, additionally developing and maintaining SPF website performance
- Designing motion graphics videos using Photoshop, illustrator, and After Effects
- designing and presenting lectures on how to protect personal information and raising awareness about electronic blackmail

# Technical Support Specialist – Watana (ISP), Erbil / Aug 2022 - Jan2023

I played a pivotal role in ensuring the seamless operation of our network infrastructure by configuring, managing, troubleshooting, and monitoring a wide range of network devices, including MikroTik, Cisco, and Ubnt hardware.

- Proficiently configured and managed servers to maintain optimal performance and reliability, ensuring uninterrupted business operations.
- Implemented and maintained best practices for server security, data backup, and disaster recovery.
- Quickly identified and resolved complex technical issues related to servers and network devices, minimizing downtime
  and ensuring minimal impact on operations.

- Provided live technical support for agents, offering remote assistance to access client computers and servers to diagnose and rectify issues promptly.
- Implemented robust network monitoring solutions to proactively identify and address performance bottlenecks and security threats.

## IT Officer-UPP, Erbil / Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

The main duties and responsibilities include:

- Data Analysis and Interpretation: Design analysis methodology, conduct descriptive analysis, interpret complex data sets, and innovate new products, tailoring outputs for diverse audiences.
- Software Development and Maintenance: Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements and design customized software solutions to streamline business processes.
- Visualization: Bring data to life using static and interactive visualizations and maps, communicating insights with clarity and creativity.
- Oversee the installation, and maintenance of hardware components such as workstations, laptops, and mobile devices. Manage software licenses and updates.
- Provide training and guidance to staff on IT best practices, security protocols, and the use of specific software applications or systems.

### **Projects**

GitHub: https://github.com/yasoua?tab=repositories

ID-Card Verification System – Duration: 1 Month

Technologies: Html, css, js, php, mysql

Achievements and Contributions: Planning, implementing and Administrator. With more than 2000 public registration with files. Auto generating cards for registration. The system uses real time barcode reader, that verifying attender's ID's. Also running on multiple devices in the same time

Al-Zawaya Management – Duration: 2 week's

Technologies: Html, css, js, laravel, mysql

Achievements and Contributions: Implemented responsive design, dashboard statistics. Public registration form with administrator.

Orders Managements – Duration 2 Week's

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysql

Achievements and Contributions: Implemented responsive design, with admin panels for admin's and users, also enable users on registration and login, online orders, with management and change state order till it user received, different payment, with invoice.

Tabiragate.org – Duration 1 Week

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysql, google console, google analytics

Achievements and Contributions: Online consultancy website with multiple responsive pages, course registration form, admin panel pages with managements, 100% SEO.

Al-Khuory Office – Duration 1 Week

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysql, google console, google analytics

Achievements and Contributions: Cars Rental website with responsive multiple pages, 100% SEO, site map, admin panel with managements.

• Archive system - Duration 2 Weeks's

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysql

Achievements and Contributions: Planning, designing and implementing modern and responsive archive system, Optimized and cleaned MySQL databases by applying normalization and indexing to the collections and schemas that helped for cost reduction and faster data retrieval, real time notification, sending emails powered by files, upload and download multiple large files, user's history pages, with database back up.

Al Rayyan Group- Duration 3 Day's

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysql

Achievements and Contributions: Restructuring the site, responsible for designing and developing arts and events department in alrayyan photography, best practice in designing front-end, 100% SEO with admin panel managements.

ERP system – <a href="https://www.h.edu.infinit-softs.com/">https://www.h.edu.infinit-softs.com/</a> Duration 3 Weeks's

Technologies: Html, css, Bootstarp, js, laravel, mysgl

Achievements and Contributions: Designing and implementing responsive ERP system, support Auth and Moderator, ORM relation, optimized and cleaned joining query table, export different and huge csv files with professional query, User restriction according privileges, CRUDS operation.

The system is online, contain 10+ pages with its operation's, it's under development and used by 250+ user.

## **Educations**

Bachelors of Science, Computer Science, 2017 – 2021, AL-Hamdaniya University, Mosul, Iraq

# Certifications

CCNA routing and switching, 2019, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq

# Languages

Arabic: Excellent - English: Excellent - Kurdish: pore

### Interests

- Reading include Self education.
- Adventures include discover new places.
- Interested in everything related to new technologies such as automation, artificial intelligence and trading stock.